bornoriginals.com 2019-03-19

# Privacy & Cookies | BornOriginals

## 1\. An overview of data protection

### General

The following gives a simple overview of what happens to your personal information when you visit our website. Personal information is any data with which you could be personally identified. Detailed information on the subject of data protection can be found in our privacy policy found below.

### Data collection on our website

#### Who is responsible for the data collection on this website?

The data collected on this website are processed by the website operator. The operator's contact details can be found in the website's required legal notice.

#### How do we collect your data?

Some data are collected when you provide it to us. This could, for example, be data you enter on a contact form.

Other data are collected automatically by our IT systems when you visit the website. These data are primarily technical data such as the browser and operating system you are using or when you accessed the page. These data are collected automatically as soon as you enter our website.

#### What do we use your data for?

Part of the data is collected to ensure the proper functioning of the website. Other data can be used to analyze how visitors use the site.

#### What rights do you have regarding your data?

You always have the right to request information about your stored data, its origin, its recipients, and the purpose of its collection at no charge. You also have the right to request that it be corrected, blocked, or deleted. You can contact us at any time using the address given in the legal notice if you have further questions about the issue of privacy and data protection. You may also, of course, file a complaint with the competent regulatory authorities.

#### Analytics and third-party tools

When visiting our website, statistical analyses may be made of your surfing behavior. This happens primarily using cookies and analytics. The analysis of your surfing behavior is usually anonymous, i.e. we will not be able to identify you from this data. You can object to this analysis or prevent it by not using certain tools. Detailed information can be found in the following privacy policy.

You can object to this analysis. We will inform you below about how to exercise your options in this regard.

## 2\. General information and mandatory information

### Data protection

The operators of this website take the protection of your personal data very seriously. We treat your personal data as confidential and in accordance with the statutory data protection regulations and this privacy policy.

If you use this website, various pieces of personal data will be collected. Personal information is any data with which you could be personally identified. This privacy policy explains what information we collect and what we use it for. It also explains how and for what purpose this happens.

Please note that data transmitted via the internet (e.g. via email communication) may be subject to security breaches. Complete protection of your data from third-party access is not possible.

### Notice concerning the party responsible for this website

The party responsible for processing data on this website is:

 Born Originals

Inh.: Melvin Lamberty

Oranienburger Str. 13

26388 Wilhelmshaven

D-Germany

Telephone: +49 176 34618782

Email: info@bornoriginals.com

The responsible party is the natural or legal person who alone or jointly with others decides on the purposes and means of processing personal data (names, email addresses, etc.).

### Revocation of your consent to the processing of your data

Many data processing operations are only possible with your express consent. You may revoke your consent at any time with future effect. An informal email making this request is sufficient. The data processed before we receive your request may still be legally processed.

### Right to file complaints with regulatory authorities

If there has been a breach of data protection legislation, the person affected may file a complaint with the competent regulatory authorities. The competent regulatory authority for matters related to data protection legislation is the data protection officer of the German state in which our company is headquartered. A list of data protection officers and their contact details can be found at the following link: https://www.bfdi.bund.de/DE/Infothek/Anschriften_Links/anschriften_links-node.html.

### Right to data portability

You have the right to have data which we process based on your consent or in fulfillment of a contract automatically delivered to yourself or to a third party in a standard, machine-readable format. If you require the direct transfer of data to another responsible party, this will only be done to the extent technically feasible.

### SSL or TLS encryption

This site uses SSL or TLS encryption for security reasons and for the protection of the transmission of confidential content, such as the inquiries you send to us as the site operator. You can recognize an encrypted connection in your browser's address line when it changes from "http://" to "https://" and the lock icon is displayed in your browser's address bar.

If SSL or TLS encryption is activated, the data you transfer to us cannot be read by third parties.

Encrypted payments on this website

If you enter into a contract which requires you to send us your payment information (e.g. account number for direct debits), we will require this data to process your payment.

Payment transactions using common means of payment (Visa/MasterCard, direct debit) are only made via encrypted SSL or TLS connections. You can recognize an encrypted connection in your browser's address line when it changes from "http://" to "https://" and the lock icon in your browser line is visible.

In the case of encrypted communication, any payment details you submit to us cannot be read by third parties.

### Information, blocking, deletion

As permitted by law, you have the right to be provided at any time with information free of charge about any of your personal data that is stored as well as its origin, the recipient and the purpose for which it has been processed. You also have the right to have this data corrected, blocked or deleted. You can contact us at any time using the address given in our legal notice if you have further questions on the topic of personal data.

### Opposition to promotional emails

We hereby expressly prohibit the use of contact data published in the context of website legal notice requirements with regard to sending promotional and informational materials not expressly requested. The website operator reserves the right to take specific legal action if unsolicited advertising material, such as email spam, is received.

## 3\. Data collection on our website

### Cookies

Some of our web pages use cookies. Cookies do not harm your computer and do not contain any viruses. Cookies help make our website more user-friendly, efficient, and secure. Cookies are small text files that are stored on your computer and saved by your browser.

Most of the cookies we use are so-called "session cookies." They are automatically deleted after your visit. Other cookies remain in your device's memory until you delete them. These cookies make it possible to recognize your browser when you next visit the site.

You can configure your browser to inform you about the use of cookies so that you can decide on a case-by-case basis whether to accept or reject a cookie. Alternatively, your browser can be configured to automatically accept cookies under certain conditions or to always reject them, or to automatically delete cookies when closing your browser. Disabling cookies may limit the functionality of this website.

Cookies which are necessary to allow electronic communications or to provide certain functions you wish to use (such as the shopping cart) are stored pursuant to Art. 6 paragraph 1, letter f of DSGVO. The website operator has a legitimate interest in the storage of cookies to ensure an optimized service provided free of technical errors. If other cookies (such as those used to analyze your surfing behavior) are also stored, they will be treated separately in this privacy policy.

### Server log files

The website provider automatically collects and stores information that your browser automatically transmits to us in "server log files". These are:

  * Browser type and browser version
  * Operating system used
  * Referrer URL
  * Host name of the accessing computer
  * Time of the server request
  * IP address

These data will not be combined with data from other sources.

The basis for data processing is Art. 6 (1) (f) DSGVO, which allows the processing of data to fulfill a contract or for measures preliminary to a contract.

### Contact form

Should you send us questions via the contact form, we will collect the data entered on the form, including the contact details you provide, to answer your question and any follow-up questions. We do not share this information without your permission.

We will, therefore, process any data you enter onto the contact form only with your consent per Art. 6 (1)(a) DSGVO. You may revoke your consent at any time. An informal email making this request is sufficient. The data processed before we receive your request may still be legally processed.

We will retain the data you provide on the contact form until you request its deletion, revoke your consent for its storage, or the purpose for its storage no longer pertains (e.g. after fulfilling your request). Any mandatory statutory provisions, especially those regarding mandatory data retention periods, remain unaffected by this provision.

### Registration on this website

You can register on our website in order to access additional functions offered here. The input data will only be used for the purpose of using the respective site or service for which you have registered. The mandatory information requested during registration must be provided in full. Otherwise, we will reject your registration.

To inform you about important changes such as those within the scope of our site or technical changes, we will use the email address specified during registration.

We will process the data provided during registration only based on your consent per Art. 6 (1)(a) DSGVO. You may revoke your consent at any time with future effect. An informal email making this request is sufficient. The data processed before we receive your request may still be legally processed.

We will continue to store the data collected during registration for as long as you remain registered on our website. Statutory retention periods remain unaffected.

### Processing of data (customer and contract data)

We collect, process, and use personal data only insofar as it is necessary to establish, or modify legal relationships with us (master data). This is done based on Art. 6 (1) (b) DSGVO, which allows the processing of data to fulfill a contract or for measures preliminary to a contract. We collect, process and use your personal data when accessing our website (usage data) only to the extent required to enable you to access our service or to bill you for the same.

Collected customer data shall be deleted after completion of the order or termination of the business relationship. Legal retention periods remain unaffected.

### Data transmitted when entering into a contract with online shops, retailers, and mail order

We transmit personally identifiable data to third parties only to the extent required to fulfill the terms of your contract, for example, to companies entrusted to deliver goods to your location or banks entrusted to process your payments. Your data will not be transmitted for any other purpose unless you have given your express permission to do so. Your data will not be disclosed to third parties for advertising purposes without your express consent.

The basis for data processing is Art. 6 (1) (b) DSGVO, which allows the processing of data to fulfill a contract or for measures preliminary to a contract.

## 4\. Analytics and advertising

### Google Analytics

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service. It is operated by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA.

Google Analytics uses so-called "cookies". These are text files that are stored on your computer and that allow an analysis of the use of the website by you. The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website is usually transmitted to a Google server in the USA and stored there.

Google Analytics cookies are stored based on Art. 6 (1) (f) DSGVO. The website operator has a legitimate interest in analyzing user behavior to optimize both its website and its advertising.

#### IP anonymization

We have activated the IP anonymization feature on this website. Your IP address will be shortened by Google within the European Union or other parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area prior to transmission to the United States. Only in exceptional cases is the full IP address sent to a Google server in the US and shortened there. Google will use this information on behalf of the operator of this website to evaluate your use of the website, to compile reports on website activity, and to provide other services regarding website activity and Internet usage for the website operator. The IP address transmitted by your browser as part of Google Analytics will not be merged with any other data held by Google.

#### Browser plugin

You can prevent these cookies being stored by selecting the appropriate settings in your browser. However, we wish to point out that doing so may mean you will not be able to enjoy the full functionality of this website. You can also prevent the data generated by cookies about your use of the website (incl. your IP address) from being passed to Google, and the processing of these data by Google, by downloading and installing the browser plugin available at the following link: https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en.

#### Objecting to the collection of data

You can prevent the collection of your data by Google Analytics by clicking on the following link: disable Google Analytics. An opt-out cookie will be set to prevent your data from being collected on future visits to this site: Disable Google Analytics.

For more information about how Google Analytics handles user data, see Google's privacy policy: https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en.

Outsourced data processing

We have entered into an agreement with Google for the outsourcing of our data processing and fully implement the strict requirements of the German data protection authorities when using Google Analytics.

Demographic data collection by Google Analytics

This website uses Google Analytics' demographic features. This allows reports to be generated containing statements about the age, gender, and interests of site visitors. This data comes from interest-based advertising from Google and third-party visitor data. This collected data cannot be attributed to any specific individual person. You can disable this feature at any time by adjusting the ads settings in your Google account or you can forbid the collection of your data by Google Analytics as described in the section "Refusal of data collection".

### Google Analytics Remarketing

Our websites use the features of Google Analytics Remarketing combined with the cross-device capabilities of Google AdWords and DoubleClick. This service is provided by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA.

This feature makes it possible to link target audiences for promotional marketing created with Google Analytics Remarketing to the cross-device capabilities of Google AdWords and Google DoubleClick. This allows advertising to be displayed based on your personal interests, identified based on your previous usage and surfing behavior on one device (e.g. your mobile phone), on other devices (such as a tablet or computer).

Once you have given your consent, Google will associate your web and app browsing history with your Google Account for this purpose. That way, any device that signs in to your Google Account can use the same personalized promotional messaging.

To support this feature, Google Analytics collects Google-authenticated IDs of users that are temporarily linked to our Google Analytics data to define and create audiences for cross-device ad promotion.

You can permanently opt out of cross-device remarketing/targeting by turning off personalized advertising in your Google Account; follow this link: https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/.

The aggregation of the data collected in your Google Account data is based solely on your consent, which you may give or withdraw from Google per Art. 6 (1) (a) DSGVO. For data collection operations not merged into your Google Account (for example, because you do not have a Google Account or have objected to the merge), the collection of data is based on Art. 6 (1) (f) DSGVO. The website operator has a legitimate interest in analyzing anonymous user behavior for promotional purposes.

For more information and the Google Privacy Policy, go to: https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/.

### Google AdWords and Google Conversion Tracking

This website uses Google AdWords. AdWords is an online advertising program from Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, United States ("Google").

As part of Google AdWords, we use so-called conversion tracking. When you click on an ad served by Google, a conversion tracking cookie is set. Cookies are small text files that your internet browser stores on your computer. These cookies expire after 30 days and are not used for personal identification of the user. Should the user visit certain pages of the website and the cookie has not yet expired, Google and the website can tell that the user clicked on the ad and proceeded to that page.

Each Google AdWords advertiser has a different cookie. Thus, cookies cannot be tracked using the website of an AdWords advertiser. The information obtained using the conversion cookie is used to create conversion statistics for the AdWords advertisers who have opted for conversion tracking. Customers are told the total number of users who clicked on their ad and were redirected to a conversion tracking tag page. However, advertisers do not obtain any information that can be used to personally identify users. If you do not want to participate in tracking, you can opt-out of this by easily disabling the Google Conversion Tracking cookie by changing your browser settings. In doing so, you will not be included in the conversion tracking statistics.

Conversion cookies are stored based on Art. 6 (1) (f) DSGVO. The website operator has a legitimate interest in analyzing user behavior to optimize both its website and its advertising.

For more information about Google AdWords and Google Conversion Tracking, see the Google Privacy Policy: https://www.google.de/policies/privacy/.

You can configure your browser to inform you about the use of cookies so that you can decide on a case-by-case basis whether to accept or reject a cookie. Alternatively, your browser can be configured to automatically accept cookies under certain conditions or to always reject them, or to automatically delete cookies when closing your browser. Disabling cookies may limit the functionality of this website.

### Facebook Pixel

Our website measures conversions using visitor action pixels from Facebook, Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA ("Facebook").

These allow the behavior of site visitors to be tracked after they click on a Facebook ad to reach the provider's website. This allows an analysis of the effectiveness of Facebook advertisements for statistical and market research purposes and their future optimization.

The data collected is anonymous to us as operators of this website and we cannot use it to draw any conclusions about our users' identities. However, the data are stored and processed by Facebook, which may make a connection to your Facebook profile and which may use the data for its own advertising purposes, as stipulated in the Facebook privacy policy. This will allow Facebook to display ads both on Facebook and on third-party sites. We have no control over how this data is used.

Check out Facebook's privacy policy to learn more about protecting your privacy: https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/.

You can also deactivate the custom audiences remarketing feature in the Ads Settings section at https://www.facebook.com/ads/preferences/?entry_product=ad_settings_screen. You will first need to log into Facebook.

If you do not have a Facebook account, you can opt out of usage-based advertising from Facebook on the website of the European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance: http://www.youronlinechoices.com/de/praferenzmanagement/.

[Disable Facebook Tracking](https://bornoriginals.com/fbPixelOptout\('Facebook-tracking%20disabled'\);)

### Hotjar

We use the following Hotjar Ltd services: heat maps, visitor records, funnel charts and form analysis, feedback polls and surveys, and recruiters. Heatmaps show anonymously which elements of a website users click. Visitor records show users who actually use the site and summarize where they move their mouse pointer and what they click. All personal information is anonymized. Funnel charts can be used to see where we have lost most of our users. Form analysis shows us exactly where within a form, for example in which field, users stop entering information. They help identify fields that confuse visitors or raise concerns. With the feedback we receive, we can capture live feedback from users to our site. Feedback polls and surveys allow us to create pop-up polls and surveys about different web pages. We can create a series of questions and give users multiple pre-formulated answers to choose from, or set up a free text field. Recruiters allow us to ask visitors for their help directly on our pages. We can invite them to participate in a live user test via screen sharing (e.g. via Skype) so we can actually see how they use our sites and what they think. The information generated by the tracking code and cookie about your website use is transferred to Hotjar and stored on servers in Ireland. Hotjar uses this information to evaluate how you use the website, to compile website activity reports for website operators and to show website operators how users use the website and what feedback they give. Hotjar uses a number of services hosted by third parties, such as Google Analytics and Optimizely. These services may collect information that is sent by your browser as part of a request on a website, such as cookies or your IP request. For more information about how Google Analytics and Optimizely collect and use your information, please see their privacy policies, which can be found here and here respectively. The cookies used by Hotjar have different durations: some are valid for 365 days, others last only until the end of the session. You can click here for the opt-out option if you choose not to use Hotjar's services (as described above): https://www.hotjar.com/opt-out. A cookie will also be placed if you shrink a test user recruitment widget. This is to ensure that the widget remains minimized while you are browsing our site. 

## 5\. Newsletter

### Newsletter data

If you would like to receive our newsletter, we require a valid email address as well as information that allows us to verify that you are the owner of the specified email address and that you agree to receive this newsletter. No additional data is collected or is only collected on a voluntary basis. We only use this data to send the requested information and do not pass it on to third parties.

We will, therefore, process any data you enter onto the contact form only with your consent per Art. 6 (1) (a) DSGVO. You can revoke consent to the storage of your data and email address as well as their use for sending the newsletter at any time, e.g. through the "unsubscribe" link in the newsletter. The data processed before we receive your request may still be legally processed.

The data provided when registering for the newsletter will be used to distribute the newsletter until you cancel your subscription when said data will be deleted. Data we have stored for other purposes (e.g. email addresses for the members area) remain unaffected.

## 6\. Plugins and tools

### Google Web Fonts

For uniform representation of fonts, this page uses web fonts provided by Google. When you open a page, your browser loads the required web fonts into your browser cache to display texts and fonts correctly.

For this purpose your browser has to establish a direct connection to Google servers. Google thus becomes aware that our web page was accessed via your IP address. The use of Google Web fonts is done in the interest of a uniform and attractive presentation of our website. This constitutes a justified interest pursuant to Art. 6 (1) (f) DSGVO.

If your browser does not support web fonts, a standard font is used by your computer.

Further information about handling user data, can be found at https://developers.google.com/fonts/faq and in Google's privacy policy at https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/.

## 7\. Payment service providers

## PayPal

Our website accepts payments via PayPal. This service is provided by PayPal (Europe) S.à.r.l & Cie, S.C.A. (22-24 Boulevard Royal, L-2449 Luxembourg).

If you choose to pay via PayPal, the payment details you provide will be sent to PayPal in accordance with art. 6 paragraph 1 letter a) (consent) and art. 6 (1) (b) DSGVO (processing for contractual purposes). You have the option to revoke your consent at any time with effect for the future. It has no influence on the processing of the data collected previously. PayPal reserves the right to carry out a credit check for the payment methods credit card via PayPal, direct debit via PayPal or - if offered - "purchase on account" via PayPal. PayPal will use the result of the credit check in relation to the statistical probability of non-payment for the purpose of deciding on the provision of the respective payment method. The credit report may contain probability values (so-called score values). If score values are included in the result of the credit report, they have their basis in a scientifically recognized mathematical-statistical procedure. Address data, among other things, is included in the calculation of the score values. Please refer to PayPal's data protection declaration for further data protection information, including information on the credit agencies used: https://www.paypal.com/de/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full

## SOFORT

If the payment method "SOFORT" is selected, payment is processed via the payment service provider SOFORT GmbH, Theresienhöhe 12, 80339 Munich, Germany (hereinafter referred to as "SOFORT"), to whom we pass on the information you provide during the ordering process as well as information about your order in accordance with Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. b DSGVO. Sofort GmbH is part of the Klarna Group (Klarna Bank AB (publ), Sveavägen 46, 11134 Stockholm, Sweden). Your data will only be passed on for the purpose of payment processing with the payment service provider SOFORT and only to the extent necessary. At the following Internet address you will find further information about the data protection regulations of SOFORT: https://www.klarna.com/sofort/datenschutz

**Boniversum & CrefoPay**

Our company regularly checks your creditworthiness when concluding contracts and, in certain cases where there is a justified interest, also for existing customers. For this purpose, we cooperate with Creditreform Boniversum GmbH, Hellersbergstraße 11, 41460 Neuss, from which we receive the necessary data. On behalf of Creditreform Boniversum, we will provide you with the following information in advance in accordance with Art. 14 EU-DSGVO: Creditreform Boniversum GmbH is a consumer information agency. It operates a database in which creditworthiness information on private individuals is stored. On this basis, Creditreform Boniversum provides credit information to its customers. Customers include credit institutions, leasing companies, insurance companies, telecommunications companies, receivables management companies, mail order, wholesale and retail companies as well as other companies that supply goods or services. Within the framework of the statutory provisions, part of the data available in the information database is also used to supply other company databases, including for address trading purposes. The Creditreform Boniversum database stores in particular information on the name, address, date of birth, e-mail address if applicable, payment behaviour and shareholdings of persons. The purpose of processing the stored data is to provide information on the creditworthiness of the person inquired about. The legal basis for the processing is Art. 6 para. 1f EU-DSGVO. Information about these data may be given thereafter only if a customer a legitimate interest in the knowledge of this information credibly demonstrates. If data is transferred to countries outside the EU, this is done on the basis of the so-called "standard contract clauses", which you can find under the following link: http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/DE/TXT/PDF/?uri=CELEX:32001D0497&from=DE or have them send to you from there. The data are stored as long as their knowledge is necessary for the fulfilment of the purpose of storage. As a rule, knowledge is required for an initial storage period of four years. After expiry, a check is made as to whether storage is still necessary, otherwise the data will be deleted to the day. If a case is settled, the data is deleted to the day three years after settlement. According to § 882e ZPO, entries in the debtor register are deleted to the day after three years have elapsed since the day of the registration order. Legitimate interests within the meaning of Art. 6 para. 1f EU-DSGVO can be: credit decision, business initiation, shareholding, claim, credit assessment, insurance contract, enforcement information. Creditreform Boniversum GmbH grants you the right to obtain information about the personal data stored about you. If the data stored about you is incorrect, you have a right to correction or deletion. If it cannot be determined immediately whether the data is incorrect or correct, you have a right to block the respective data until clarification. If your data are incomplete, you can demand their completion. If you have given your consent to the processing of the data stored at Creditreform Boniversum, you have the right to revoke this consent at any time. The revocation does not affect the legality of the processing of your data on the basis of your consent until any revocation. Should you have any objections, requests or complaints regarding data protection, you can contact the Creditreform Boniversum Data Protection Officer at any time. He or she will help you quickly and confidentially with all questions relating to data protection. You can also complain about the processing of data by Boniversum to the State Data Protection Officer responsible for your federal state. The data that Creditreform Boniversum has stored on you comes from publicly accessible sources, from debt collection agencies and from their clients. To describe your creditworthiness, Creditreform Boniversum creates a score for your data. The score value includes data on age and gender, address data and, in some cases, payment experience data. These data flow into the score value calculation with different weightings. Creditreform Boniversum customers use the scores as a tool for making their own credit decisions.

Right of objection:

The data stored at Creditreform Boniversum is processed for compelling reasons worthy of protection in terms of creditor and creditor protection, which regularly outweigh your interests, rights and freedoms, or serves to assert, exercise or defend legal claims. You can only object to the processing of your data by Creditreform Boniversum in the case of reasons which arise from a particular situation in which you find yourself and which must be proven. If such special reasons can be proven to exist, the data will no longer be processed there. Creditreform Boniversum GmbH, Hellersbergstr. 11, 41460 Neuss, Germany, is responsible within the meaning of Art. 4 No. 7 EU Data Protection Act. Your contact in our company is the Consumer Service, Tel.: 02131 36845560, Fax: 02131 36845570, E-Mail: selbstauskunft@boniversum.de. You can reach our data protection officer at the following contact details: Creditreform Boniversum GmbH, Data Protection Officer, Hellersbergstr. 11, 41460 Neuss, Germany, e-mail: datenschutz@boniversum.de.
